<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-21T23:34:38+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Portfolio - Ankita Parida</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><entry><title type="html">3 Proven Instagram Strategies to Take Your Cannabis Business to the Next Level</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/cannabis-insta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 Proven Instagram Strategies to Take Your Cannabis Business to the Next Level" /><published>2021-10-21T20:20:32+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-21T20:20:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/cannabis-insta</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/cannabis-insta/">&lt;p&gt;Setting up a Social Media Marketing strategy is hard. 
Adding to that, putting social media and Cannabis into the mix makes it even more trickier - how to take your dispensary business to the next level when Instagram is known to be somewhat hostile to the promotion of Cannabis businesses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram has laid out a few guidelines for the promotion of Cannabis dispensaries on its platform. So, if you follow those, there’s no reason to miss out on the enormous marketing reach it has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the sale of any canna products is essentially not permitted via the site, you can and should, at the very least, use its might to build and promote your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We conducted research and studied strategies that have worked out for businesses operating in the same realm. We sifted through several cannabis business pages that have a high rate of engagement (50-100 comments or more on each post) and an incredibly loyal following (thousands of followers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are &lt;b&gt;3 proven strategies&lt;/b&gt; we found that you can incorporate into your Instagram marketing plan right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-pick-an-aesthetic-to-build-your-brand-identity&quot;&gt;1. Pick an aesthetic to build your brand identity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are few things more powerful than building a brand. People recognize a brand - that is known knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But developing an aesthetic? Now, that’s something not many pages tend to concentrate on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Reel people in by setting and sticking with an aesthetic that matches the energy of the culture and industry you are in and watch your following grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Picking a well-loved aesthetic would require gaining insight into the minds and expectations of your future followers and the product you are selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-regularly-post-some-lit-content-pun-intended&quot;&gt;2. Regularly post some lit content (pun intended)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It sounds like your average, run-of-the-mill advice.  But what exactly constitutes “great content” in this sphere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It gets tricky because Instagram doesn’t like to see posts that directly mention in text or show pictures of cannabis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So where does that leave us? Let’s discuss how to keep your content calendar full and updated for months in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;educational-content&quot;&gt;Educational content&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take advantage of this opportunity and educate people about the varieties you sell, the industry in general, the history behind it, trailblazers in the community who paved the way to where we stand today, the chemistry and biology of what happens once it enters our bodies, why and how it’s deemed medicinal, to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The key is to position your content as strictly educational instead of commercial.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;latest-news-pertaining-to-your-city-state-country-or-the-industry-in-general&quot;&gt;Latest news (pertaining to your city, state, country, or the industry in general)&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There’s always some new and interesting development taking place around the world regarding this up-and-coming industry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get your users up to speed with the latest news and keep them well-informed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;host-qas&quot;&gt;Host Q&amp;amp;As:&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Q&amp;amp;As can be an excellent source of connecting with your audience and essentially doing market research.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ask people about their pattern of cannabis consumption, their favorite places to go or activities to do when they are baked, their favorite munchies, anything they’d like to see in the market that is missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use it as a tool that serves the dual purpose of striking a chord with your following and assessing the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;share-behind-the-scenes-of-running-and-growing-wink-your-business&quot;&gt;Share behind-the-scenes of running and growing (*wink) your business:&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bring visibility to your backend efforts. It could be a parade you attended that celebrated legalization in a state or country, or a campaign your founders or employees back that supports the cause and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As long as it feels sincere, your followers will be delighted to learn more about you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-support-a-cause-greater-than-yourself&quot;&gt;3. Support a cause greater than yourself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just because you run or contribute adjacently to the cannabis business, doesn’t mean you have to confine your identity to your cause only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bring attention to and show your solidarity towards causes and people trying to do their bit for changing the world for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People want to support brands that aren’t one-dimensional and contribute to the betterment of society. It doesn’t hurt to have followers who actually think you are a living body, not just a front for business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these strategies are tried and tested and guaranteed to push your engagement through the roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add these strategies to your Instagram marketing plan and see your campaign turn into a huge success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="B2B" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html">Setting up a Social Media Marketing strategy is hard. Adding to that, putting social media and Cannabis into the mix makes it even more trickier - how to take your dispensary business to the next level when Instagram is known to be somewhat hostile to the promotion of Cannabis businesses?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An NGO with a mission to reduce food waste</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/foodcircle-article/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An NGO with a mission to reduce food waste" /><published>2021-10-21T20:20:32+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-21T20:20:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/foodcircle-article</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/foodcircle-article/">&lt;p&gt;Food wastage has become a dire issue that is growing in scale as the need to feed the growing population of the world is skyrocketing every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we go any further, let’s look at three mind-blowing food waste statistics :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If food loss were a country, it would be the &lt;a href=&quot;https://earth.org/facts-about-food-waste/&quot;&gt;third-largest&lt;/a&gt; greenhouse gas emitter, behind China and the US.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The water used to produce the food wasted could be used by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theworldcounts.com/stories/food-waste-facts&quot;&gt;9,000,000,000(bn)&lt;/a&gt; people at around 200 liters per person per day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The food currently wasted in Europe could feed 200,000,000(million) people, lost or wasted food in Latin America could feed 300,000,000(million) people and, in Africa, it could feed 300,000,000(million) people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you see the number of zeroes trailing those figures? Quite understandably, it’s hard to wrap our minds around figures so large while seeing tiny instances of food getting wasted in our everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the matter of curbing food waste is an urgent one, as its economic and environmental impact is along the lines of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To discuss this matter further, we have with us today Konstantina, who’s in charge of Social Media and Promotion at foodsquare.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: Hello Konstantina! Welcome to this interview and thank you for participating in the project Food Waste Around the World. Before we begin, can you tell a little bit about yourself and where are you from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you for having me today. I hail from a little town in Greece. Five years ago, I decided that I would move abroad and I began working on this internship in Amsterdam recently.
Amsterdam has so many opportunities to offer - it’s safe to say that it truly has something for everyone. I knew I could find and try different things here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: Interesting. And how is the food waste situation in Greece? Is it a big issue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Konstantina: I grew up seeing my family and the people around me buy large quantities of food and groceries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the same time, I saw the stark reality of people starving on the streets - next to garbage cans, unable to buy food for themselves. I think this is one of the reasons behind my sensitivity towards food wastage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s sad to see but, not enough people are working on it or are even sentient of this issue. Most of the food waste comes from fruits and vegetables in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to a survey conducted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.respectfood.com/article/11-facts-about-food-wastage/&quot;&gt;Respect Food&lt;/a&gt;, 63% of people don’t know the difference between “use by” and “best before” dates. Foods with “use by” dates are perishable and must be eaten before the given date. Foods with “best before” dates can be eaten after the given date, but they won’t be at their best quality. In developing countries, 40% of losses occur at the post-harvest and processing stages, while in developed countries, more than 40% of losses occur at the retail and consumer levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: Yeah, I agree. Who is really driving the attention on the food waste issue there? Are there any NGOs or small communities that work on this? Do you know of any initiatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: I know there are several non-profit organisations and NGOs who are actively tackling this issue. They organize activities and campaigns to prevent food waste.I participated in volunteering activities where we provided food for people that included immigrants and refugees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These initiatives are taken on a local level, but sadly, they are not so widespread. I’ve noticed that there’s not a lot of articles or advertisement campaigns for driving people’s attention to this issue in any city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: Interesting. So you have been living in Amsterdam for a while now. Have you noticed any difference in what you see in the Netherlands as compared to Greece, regarding the food waste situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: I was pleasantly surprised to see a lot of initiatives being taken here in this regard. I could see that the network here is far and wide. There’s a broad range of initiatives that curb food waste and spread awareness among people. You can see the various ways food waste is reimagined instead of being wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In developing countries, 40% of losses occur at the post-harvest and processing stages, while in developed countries, more than 40% of losses occur at the retail and consumer levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: I see. Thinking about your country, what do you think could be the next possible step of action by different groups or NGOs, and also the government to reduce food waste?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: I’m yet to see any particular interest or huge initiatives taken by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think all of them should try to achieve more visibility and promote their actions through digital channels and social media to send this message across to young people. Having grown up in fairly prosperous households, they tend to have little sensitivity towards food wastage than say, middle-aged people. Having more than enough food has led to them taking it for granted. This attitude needs to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: Absolutely. Anything you would like to add?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: Yes, a few words about the kind of thinking I just touched upon. When we go to restaurants, if they bring us a decent portion of food, we complain that we paid too much to deserve such small portions. But if they bring us huge portions, we feel satisfied even when we don’t finish it all, eventually contributing to wastage. This needs to change and it’s up to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do believe changing our outlook will be a small step in the right direction. That is all I wanted to add. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The EU and Member States are committed to meeting the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDG), adopted in September 2015, including a target to halve per capita food waste at the retail and consumer level by 2030 and reduce food losses along the food production and supply chains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aligned with Konstantina’s beliefs, fruits and vegetables do have the highest wastage rates, followed by meat and milk. Annual per capita household food waste (in kilograms per year) of Greece is among the highest in the world at 142, next to only Nigeria at 189, as of 2020, according to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/933059/per-capita-food-waste-of-selected-countries/&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by Statista.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It remains a grim situation but with the help of NGOs and other institutions, this matter can capture the greater part of the public’s attention and change for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to raise awareness about this issue or educate yourself, here are a few food waste initiatives operating in Greece that you can be a part of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boroume.gr/en/&quot;&gt;BOROUME&lt;/a&gt; is a non-profit organisation that fights food waste by organizing the distribution of surplus food for charity throughout Greece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;https://artosdrasi.rei.gr/&quot;&gt;Bread and Action&lt;/a&gt; collects and distributes large edible food leftovers or cooked food, to needy service centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sustainablegastronomy.eu/blog.aspx&quot;&gt;Sustainablegastronomy&lt;/a&gt; has a blog that regularly shares information about the practices and impacts revolving around food waste and management incentives in Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wastage of food is a blatant affront to all the resources that go into producing, packaging, and distributing it. It not only affects the people and the economy in myriad ways, but it harms major natural resources such as air, water, and land. To reduce food waste, we need to focus on all aspects of the supply chain and increase the quality and quantity of governmental regulations, to name a few. Needless to say, educating the public about the consequences of food waste and management must be one of the top priorities so that we can all play our small roles in tackling this epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drawdown.org/solutions/reduced-food-waste&quot;&gt;drawdown.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rubicon.com/blog/food-waste-facts/&quot;&gt;rubicon.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.respectfood.com/article/11-facts-about-food-wastage/&quot;&gt;respectfood.com&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://stopwastingfoodmovement.org/food-waste/food-waste-facts/&quot;&gt;stopwastingfoodmovement.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theworldcounts.com/stories/food-waste-facts&quot;&gt;theworldcounts.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://earth.org/facts-about-food-waste/&quot;&gt;earth.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eu-fusions.org/index.php/country-reports/reports/294-greece&quot;&gt;eu-fusions.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="B2B" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html">Food wastage has become a dire issue that is growing in scale as the need to feed the growing population of the world is skyrocketing every day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ifeel, Madrid based health-tech startup with an aim to democratize access to therapy, raises €5.5M</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/press-release/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ifeel, Madrid based health-tech startup with an aim to democratize access to therapy, raises €5.5M" /><published>2021-10-21T20:20:32+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-21T20:20:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/press-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/press-release/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;ifeels-mission-is-to-facilitate-personalized-online-therapy-with-the-help-of-licensed-health-professionals-based-on-a-subscription-model&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ifeel’s mission is to facilitate personalized online therapy with the help of licensed health professionals, based on a subscription model.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Madrid, Spain., May. 5, 2021&lt;/strong&gt; – ifeel, the disruptive mental health-focused startup, has scored €5.5M in Series A funding led by pan-European Venture Capital firm, Nauta Capital.&lt;br /&gt;
Ifeel is reimagining people’s approach towards caring for their mental health, both on personal and professional fronts. Founded in 2017 as a customer-centric platform, it transitioned to a hybrid model in 2020, answering to a rise in demand from companies looking to invest in the mental well-being of their employees. So, the service is available starting with weekly subscriptions for individuals or under employer’s or insurance provider’s cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ifeel stands out from mindfulness apps and other therapy platforms with the help of its AI-powered platform and range of services that focus on providing personalized support. It facilitates one-on-one video therapy sessions with licensed psychologists along with delivering self-care tools like daily mood trackers, guided chats and recommended activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The health crisis and new blended employment models create a high need for managers to support remote employees and distant customers”, says Amir Kaplan, CEO, and co-founder of ifeel. “We believe smart emotional support services will be a must-have benefit in the near future as the impact is so high. The safe and anonymous access to ifeel allows employees to improve their life with no need of manager referral,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comment from Jordi Vinas, General Partner at Nauta Capital aligns with the company’s mission. “We believe iFeel’s approach has an edge over competitors, thanks to having a holistic platform that covers both prevention and intervention and that includes multiple user touchpoints (self-care tools and guided chat and 1-on-1 video therapies), combined with its full integration to business and distribution partners and its global coverage in several languages. We’re excited to join the team in their journey to truly transform the emotional well-being space.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following a monumental shift in how we define ‘working’ nowadays, it makes complete sense to acknowledge the mental toll it has and will require going forward. ifeel aims to be the bold new solution that equips you with its unique set of self-care tools and therapy services to care for your mental health and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About ifeel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ifeel aims to democratize therapy and remove the luxurious aspect attached to it. It’s an AI-powered, emotional well-being platform that offers one-on-one therapy sessions with licensed psychologists and various other self-care tools to empower you to take better care of your mental health. Learn more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifeelonline.com/en/&quot;&gt;ifeelonline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="B2B" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html">ifeel’s mission is to facilitate personalized online therapy with the help of licensed health professionals, based on a subscription model.</summary></entry></feed>