<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-07T20:50:43+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Portfolio - Ankita Parida</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><entry><title type="html">Technical Writing Sample</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/api-versioning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technical Writing Sample" /><published>2021-11-11T19:20:32+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T19:20:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/api-versioning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/api-versioning/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;api-versioning-and-support-cycle&quot;&gt;API Versioning and Support Cycle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;versioning&quot;&gt;Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABC supports versioning so that our internal and external stakeholders (developers, users, businesses) can stay up-to-date with changes and new releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://semver.org/&quot;&gt;Semantic Versioning 2.0.0&lt;/a&gt; convention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Versions are named as follows: MAJOR.MINOR.PATCH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Major&lt;/strong&gt; version is released when backwards-incompatible (outlined below) changes are implemented. Following is a non-exhaustive list of changes that warrants a major version release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removal of an API endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removal of an API attribute&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change in any API data formats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Database changes which can not be migrated automatically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change in script syntax, which may break existing scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Minor&lt;/strong&gt; version is released on the implementation of backwards-compatible (outlined below) changes. Following is a non-exhaustive list of changes that warrants a minor version release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addition of an API endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addition of an API attribute&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Database changes which can be migrated automatically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change in script syntax which can be migrated automatically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Patch&lt;/strong&gt; version is released with bug fixes and minor improvements which do not cause any backward incompatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;v1.3.2 - signifies this is the first major release. It has 3 minor versions with 2 patches in this minor version
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;curious-about-the-latest-changes&quot;&gt;Curious about the latest changes?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current version is &lt;strong&gt;v3.4.3&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more information about our version timelines, release dates and changes on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://fakelink.com/releases&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deprecation&quot;&gt;Deprecation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep our services in line with customer expectations, certain outdated features are replaced with better functionalities from time to time. APIs are also deprecated to minimize critical security risks and to ensure legal compliance. We take the following steps to mitigate the effect of API deprecations and make the transition smoother for our users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feature deprecations are released with a minor version.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part of the feature (which needs to be changed) is deprecated before introducing the backwards-incompatible change. This ensures a wide window for clients to prepare for the upcoming change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An alternative is usually available at the time of deprecation so no additional transition time is needed once the backwards-incompatible change is introduced.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deprecated APIs are announced in the changelog of the release where the deprecation was introduced to keep users informed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;support-cycle&quot;&gt;Support cycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provide support to each major version for a period of at least two years starting from the first release of that major version. The support cycle for the latest major version is continued until a new major version is released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the support period, we do not add minor releases to past major versions, but we may add patch updates if required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not adhere to a fixed release schedule. Our efforts are always geared towards keeping the platform stable with the least amount of incompatible changes. We aim to minimize the number of major releases and guarantee that there won’t be more than one major release per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankita396.github.io/portfolio/&quot;&gt;knowledge base&lt;/a&gt; to discover more about our API lifecycle management.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="API" /><category term="Techinical Writing" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html">API Versioning and Support Cycle</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Article Sample</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/Carbon_pricing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Article Sample" /><published>2021-11-05T19:20:32+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-05T19:20:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/Carbon_pricing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/Carbon_pricing/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;carbon-pricing---is-it-the-end-all-be-all-solution-to-fight-climate-change&quot;&gt;Carbon pricing - is it the end all be all solution to fight climate change?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbon pricing has dominated the list of buzzworthy terms related to climate action lately, partly due to the much discussed event COP26, held last year. It’s been touted as an effective tool to combat rising levels of greenhouse gas(GHG) emissions by experts and pundits all over the world. 
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;But&lt;/strong&gt; how effective has it been in producing real, tangible results in terms of reducing overall emissions and decarbonizing the environment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbon pricing works by either levying taxes on emissions via a carbon tax or limiting the amount of emissions allowed for industries via Emissions Trading Scheme (ETS), to put it simply. In this article, we’ll take a closer look at ETS. And to better understand the cracks and faults in the system, it is imperative to have a general idea of how this scheme works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ets-and-how-it-works&quot;&gt;ETS and how it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETS is an interesting mechanism for incentivizing firms to keep their carbon emissions under check. Under the Emissions Trading Scheme, a market is established for the trading of emissions as commodities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Companies that are huge in scale and involved in carbon-intensive operations receive free or traded allowances annually.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The government sets a ceiling on the amount of allowances available for all (cap). Each year, the cap is lowered in order to lessen the gross emissions and achieve the reduction targets. (The EU had set a goal of 21% reduction in emissions by 2020 from the threshold set in 2005 and 43% reduction by 2030). It is therefore, also called the cap-and-trade principle.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Companies surrender an amount of allowances equivalent to their annual emissions of GHG in tonnes (one allowance grants them the consent to emit 1 tonne of CO2).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who produce more than their allocated share must purchase more via trade or auction to compensate for the deficit. Those who produce less than their share are free to trade those allowances to companies or industries in deficit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, this scheme was supposed to push firms to switch to low carbon technologies, invest more in R&amp;amp;D and look for better alternatives to keep the carbon footprint of their entire supply chain well below the expected level. But the reality has been confoundingly different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wherein-lies-the-problem&quot;&gt;Wherein lies the problem?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market’s influence on this scheme gives the notion that it creates a fair playing ground for all participants, but it’s not entirely the case, as it has worked somewhat in favor of the firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the supply and demand parameters involved, the price of emissions per tonne of Co2 is usually extremely low in most countries. The carbon prices have been well below the estimated ‘social cost of carbon’ - cost associated with the environmental and health effects of greenhouse gas emissions. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/fandd/2019/12/the-case-for-carbon-taxation-and-putting-a-price-on-pollution-parry.htm&quot;&gt;IMF estimates&lt;/a&gt; that the average global price for carbon is &lt;strong&gt;$2 per tonne&lt;/strong&gt;, while a conservative estimate put together by the Carbon Pricing Leadership Coalition (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonpricingleadership.org/report-of-the-highlevel-commission-on-carbon-prices&quot;&gt;CPLC&lt;/a&gt;) puts the SCC between &lt;strong&gt;$50 and $100&lt;/strong&gt; by 2030. As you can see, the current prices are simply not enough to offset the current levels of carbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality regarding the success of countries with decent carbon prices like Sweden with the current price of US$119 per ton (World Bank Group &lt;a href=&quot;https://openknowledge.worldbank.org/handle/10986/33809&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt;) also presents a dismal result. Allocating a higher price has still not led to considerable reductions in emissions per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-that-all&quot;&gt;Is that all?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardly. Then there’s the matter of carbon leakage that is overwhelmingly underreported and ignored. Firms and businesses are responsible for monitoring their emissions strictly occurring within their countries. The current structure involving non standardized policy and pricing across jurisdictions and countries gives way to businesses moving their operations elsewhere to keep their emissions low on paper. Hence, the term &lt;strong&gt;“carbon leakage”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have also been a few cases of misreporting of total emissions by huge firms such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/jan/31/australian-regulator-finds-large-scale-emissions-misreporting-by-coalminer-peabody#:~:text=Australian%20regulator%20finds%20large%2Dscale%20emissions%20misreporting%20by%20coalminer%20Peabody,-US%20giant%20agrees&amp;amp;text=The%20total%20error%20was%20large,largely%20cancelled%20each%20other%20out.&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; incident. The onus to diligently record and report their total emissions falls on firms, and while there are regulators in place to oversee that, it’s not a reach to assume that not all the reportings are checked for inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another&lt;/strong&gt; critique that could be leveled is that certain industries, such as electricity, are heavily under the lens because of the relative ease of tracking the fixed sources of generation and distribution. On the other hand, industries like agro-food where there are a number of highly variable parameters (dietary habits, soil conditions, climate, to name a few) are not easy to assess and price effectively. As a result, quite a few industries that are heavy polluters are still not under the pricing policy and therefore have no incentive to check their emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, businesses have not made strides in changing technologies and methodologies, as the price to pay for doing business as usual is lower than shifting towards more climate friendly options. Unsurprisingly, these pricing measures &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0301421518304063&quot;&gt;haven’t incentivized innovations&lt;/a&gt; in the field of clean energy or low carbon technologies as popularly believed. Businesses have instead gone on to choose the least expensive option that fulfills their obligations to their governments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-next&quot;&gt;So, what next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carbon pricing as the primary means of combating the carbon menace is not the best school of thought to follow. Real, tangible change that can be brought on by steps such as phasing out coal, removing subsidies for fossil fuel industries, shifting away from the reliance on carbon intensive technologies are a few compelling steps needed right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right way forward would be to run a tight ship of administrators and regulators who would determine fair yet effective carbon prices, keep track of the allowances in emissions tradings, monitor and prevent carbon leakage, while encouraging more businesses to adopt systematic changes in their workings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To pave the way for better policies, policy makers and leaders need to effectively communicate to people from all walks of life, about their varying roles in shouldering the shift to a greener economy. The most vulnerable portion of the population would need the most support in fiscal and educational terms to cushion this transition. After all, no significant change can be brought on without holding the major culprits accountable and including the most vulnerable to the discourse.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="Article" /><category term="Article writing" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html">Carbon pricing - is it the end all be all solution to fight climate change?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Email Newsletter Sample</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/email-newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Email Newsletter Sample" /><published>2021-05-21T20:20:32+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-21T20:20:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/email-newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/email-newsletter/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio/assets/img/Employee-Newsletter-Sample.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="Email" /><category term="newsletter" /><category term="B2C" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Feature Article sample</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/foodcircle-article/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feature Article sample" /><published>2021-05-21T20:20:32+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-21T20:20:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/foodcircle-article</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/foodcircle-article/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;foodsquare-a-social-enterprise-with-a-mission-to-reduce-food-waste&quot;&gt;FoodSquare, a social enterprise with a mission to reduce food waste&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food wastage has become a dire issue that is growing in scale as the need to feed the growing population of the world skyrockets every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we go any further, let’s look at three &lt;strong&gt;mind-blowing food waste statistics&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If food loss were a country, it would be the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://earth.org/facts-about-food-waste/&quot;&gt;third-largest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; greenhouse gas emitter, behind China and the US.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The water used to produce the food wasted could be used by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theworldcounts.com/stories/food-waste-facts&quot;&gt;9,000,000,000(bn)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; people at around 200 liters per person per day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The food currently wasted in Europe could feed &lt;strong&gt;200,000,000(million)&lt;/strong&gt; people, lost or wasted food in Latin America could feed &lt;strong&gt;300,000,000(million)&lt;/strong&gt; people and, in Africa, it could feed &lt;strong&gt;300,000,000(million)&lt;/strong&gt; people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you see the number of zeroes trailing those figures? Quite understandably, it’s hard to wrap our minds around figures so large while seeing tiny instances of food getting wasted in our everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the matter of curbing food waste is an urgent one, as its economic and environmental impact is along the lines of global warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To discuss this matter further, we have with us today Konstantina, who’s in charge of Social Media and Promotion at foodsquare.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Hello Konstantina! Welcome to this interview and thank you for participating in the project Food Waste Around the World. Before we begin, can you tell a little bit about yourself and where are you from?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you for having me today. I hail from a little town in Greece. Five years ago, I decided that I would move abroad and I began working on this internship in Amsterdam recently.
Amsterdam has so many opportunities to offer - it’s safe to say that it truly has something for everyone. I knew I could find and try different things here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Interesting. And how is the food waste situation in Greece? Is it a big issue?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Konstantina: I grew up seeing my family and the people around me buy large quantities of food and groceries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the same time, I saw the stark reality of people starving on the streets - next to garbage cans, unable to buy food for themselves. I think this is one of the reasons behind my sensitivity towards food wastage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s sad to see but, not enough people are working on it or are even sentient of this issue. Most of the food waste comes from fruits and vegetables in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to a survey conducted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.respectfood.com/article/11-facts-about-food-wastage/&quot;&gt;Respect Food&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;63%&lt;/strong&gt; of people don’t know the difference between &lt;strong&gt;“use by”&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;“best before”&lt;/strong&gt; dates. Foods with “use by” dates are perishable and must be eaten before the given date. Foods with “best before” dates can be eaten after the given date, but they won’t be at their best quality. In developing countries, 40% of losses occur at the post-harvest and processing stages, while in developed countries, more than 40% of losses occur at the retail and consumer levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Yeah, I agree. Who is really driving the attention on the food waste issue there? Are there any NGOs or small communities that work on this? Do you know of any initiatives?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: I know there are several non-profit organisations and NGOs who are actively tackling this issue. They organize activities and campaigns to prevent food waste.I participated in volunteering activities where we provided food for people that included immigrants and refugees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These initiatives are taken on a local level, but sadly, they are not so widespread. I’ve noticed that there’s not a lot of articles or advertisement campaigns for driving people’s attention to this issue in any city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Interesting. So you have been living in Amsterdam for a while now. Have you noticed any difference in what you see in the Netherlands as compared to Greece, regarding the food waste situation?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: I was pleasantly surprised to see a lot of initiatives being taken here in this regard. I could see that the network here is far and wide. There’s a broad range of initiatives that curb food waste and spread awareness among people. You can see the various ways food waste is reimagined instead of being wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;developing countries, 40%&lt;/strong&gt; of losses occur at the post-harvest and processing stages, while in &lt;strong&gt;developed countries, more than 40%&lt;/strong&gt; of losses occur at the retail and consumer levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;I see. Thinking about your country, what do you think could be the next possible step of action by different groups or NGOs, and also the government to reduce food waste?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: I’m yet to see any particular interest or huge initiatives taken by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think all of them should try to achieve more visibility and promote their actions through digital channels and social media to send this message across to young people. Having grown up in fairly prosperous households, they tend to have little sensitivity towards food wastage than say, middle-aged people. Having more than enough food has led to them taking it for granted. This attitude needs to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Absolutely. Anything you would like to add?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konstantina&lt;/strong&gt;: Yes, a few words about the kind of thinking I just touched upon. When we go to restaurants, if they bring us a decent portion of food, we complain that we paid too much to deserve such small portions. But if they bring us huge portions, we feel satisfied even when we don’t finish it all, eventually contributing to wastage. This needs to change and it’s up to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do believe changing our outlook will be a small step in the right direction. That is all I wanted to add. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The EU and Member States are committed to meeting the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDG), adopted in September 2015, including a target to halve per capita food waste at the retail and consumer level by 2030 and reduce food losses along the food production and supply chains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aligned with Konstantina’s beliefs, &lt;strong&gt;fruits and vegetables do have the highest wastage rates, followed by meat and milk&lt;/strong&gt;. Annual per capita household food waste (in kilograms per year) of &lt;strong&gt;Greece is among the highest in the world at 142, next to only Nigeria at 189&lt;/strong&gt;, as of 2020, according to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/933059/per-capita-food-waste-of-selected-countries/&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by Statista.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It remains a grim situation but with the help of NGOs and other institutions, this matter can capture the greater part of the public’s attention and change for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to raise awareness about this issue or educate yourself, here are a few food waste initiatives operating in Greece that you can be a part of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boroume.gr/en/&quot;&gt;BOROUME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a non-profit organisation that fights food waste by organizing the distribution of surplus food for charity throughout Greece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://artosdrasi.rei.gr/&quot;&gt;Bread and Action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; collects and distributes large edible food leftovers or cooked food, to needy service centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sustainablegastronomy.eu/blog.aspx&quot;&gt;Sustainablegastronomy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has a blog that regularly shares information about the practices and impacts revolving around food waste and management incentives in Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wastage of food is a blatant affront to all the resources that go into producing, packaging, and distributing it. It not only affects the people and the economy in myriad ways, but it harms major natural resources such as air, water, and land. To reduce food waste, we need to focus on all aspects of the supply chain and increase the quality and quantity of governmental regulations, to name a few. Needless to say, educating the public about the consequences of food waste and management must be one of the top priorities so that we can all play our small roles in tackling this epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drawdown.org/solutions/reduced-food-waste&quot;&gt;drawdown.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rubicon.com/blog/food-waste-facts/&quot;&gt;rubicon.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.respectfood.com/article/11-facts-about-food-wastage/&quot;&gt;respectfood.com&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://stopwastingfoodmovement.org/food-waste/food-waste-facts/&quot;&gt;stopwastingfoodmovement.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theworldcounts.com/stories/food-waste-facts&quot;&gt;theworldcounts.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://earth.org/facts-about-food-waste/&quot;&gt;earth.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eu-fusions.org/index.php/country-reports/reports/294-greece&quot;&gt;eu-fusions.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="Feature Article" /><category term="B2C" /><category term="Marketing" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html">FoodSquare, a social enterprise with a mission to reduce food waste Food wastage has become a dire issue that is growing in scale as the need to feed the growing population of the world skyrockets every day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SEO Content Writing Sample</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/SEO-Content-Sample-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SEO Content Writing Sample" /><published>2021-05-21T20:20:32+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-21T20:20:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/SEO-Content-Sample-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/SEO-Content-Sample-1/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;can-i-paint-my-aluminum-window-frames&quot;&gt;Can I Paint My Aluminum Window Frames?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being exposed to the elements 24/7 does great damage to your house. Windows are among the many that take a constant beating. If your windows are made of aluminum or any other metal, then you must know from first-hand experience that they lose their shine and look dull after a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be wondering whether you can paint aluminum window frames or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to that is &lt;strong&gt;yes, you can paint your aluminium window frames and get them to look good as new in no time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this article, you will find answers to:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to Make Aluminum Window Frames Look Better?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the cost to paint aluminum window frames?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to Make Old Aluminum Windows Look New?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to Date Old Windows? / How old are my windows?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-make-aluminum-window-frames-look-better&quot;&gt;How to Make Aluminum Window Frames Look Better?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a pity that aluminum window frames weather scratches, dullness, discoloration and lose their sheen over time. Painting them is an easy and inexpensive process to refurbish their tired, worn look. Let’s explore how to paint and give your aluminum window frames a complete makeover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety precautions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DIY projects are fun and extremely satisfying. But taking safety precautions while handling such chemical substances is paramount. Wear gloves, safety goggles and respirators or masks while performing the next steps and keep your vicinity well ventilated to prevent buildup of toxic chemicals in the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also advisable to protect your glass panes and surrounding walls while you perform this entire operation. Use Painter’s tape to seal off the glass from the frame and masking paper or plastic to protect the rest of the glass area. Also, use drip sheets on the floor to keep them from staining or any paint mishap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleaning your frames&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s tricky to make paint adhere to metal surfaces. It’s even trickier when there is dust, grime and debris present between the metal and paint coats. It’s therefore, necessary to clean your window frames thoroughly before moving on to the next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can clean your frames using a no-soap or mild soap solution and a soft cloth. Micro-fiber cloth would be the gentlest option. If there is any indication of rust, try using a soft sandpaper to remove the layers and clean the remains. Make sure to pat dry the frames, especially the grooves and joints, so that there is no water deposit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applying Primer&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priming is an essential step that, however tempting it may seem, should not be missed. Priming provides the metal surface with a smooth finish and prepares it to accept paint coats flawlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primer you choose should be oil-based and primarily come with rust-inhibitive properties. You could also go for self-etching primers as they lend enhanced adhesion to the paint. You can get a paint brush or roller to apply the primer or go for various spray paint primers. Spray paint primers are preferred as they help in applying thin coats which is the key to give your aluminum window frames a high-finish, professional look after the paint job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After applying primer to your window frames, let that primer settle for a few hours before you start with the painting process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applying Paint&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that your window frames are cleaned, primed and fully prepped, they are ready to be painted over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-quality acrylic paints tend to be the best kind of paints for aluminum window frames. Make sure to check the paint instructions beforehand and verify if it’s suitable to be used on aluminum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, metal spray paints are a great option to reduce any incidence of excess buildup or dripping. Spray paints are easier to handle and manuever in order to render thin coats of paint which is essential to achieve an even finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your application should be steady with back and forth movements, all the while ensuring that the coats are even and thin. Let layers dry for a few minutes in case of spray paints and a period of 6-7 hours in case of acrylic paint before going for more layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave your paint to dry and check for any textural defects. If you find any, scrape them off with a sleak blade causing minimum damage. Voila! Your window frames will be looking as good as new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-cost-to-paint-aluminum-window-frames&quot;&gt;What is the cost to paint aluminum window frames?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole cost of the project would depend upon the size and number of window frames you need to paint. If you have a few window frames to paint, then it’s safe to estimate that you will be able to wrap up the &lt;strong&gt;whole project in under $150&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have a lot of area to cover, then you might have to compare the cost of doing it all by yourself with hiring professionals for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, it’d take around one to two standard cans of spray for a single large window. Considering this and that you have the cleaning supplies and other optional supplies like ladder at hand, here’s the rest of your cost estimate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A can of spray paint: $10-$15 for 12oz,
Or, Acrylic paint: $45 to $50 per gallon,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Paint Primer: $15 to $25 per gallon,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Drop Cloth: $10-$30&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Scrub Brush: $10-$25&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tape and paper to protect surfaces: $5 each, per roll&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going the DIY route for painting your aluminum window frames would be considerably lower in cost than replacing them or hiring a contractor. For this task, you will need supplies such as masking paper, painter’s tape, drop clothes, sandpaper, safety goggles, ladder etc in addition to the primer and paint. If you choose to go for spraying your primer and paint, you will save on time and costs since you can skip out on buying paint brushes or rollers. Spray paints also dry faster than other kinds of paints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-make-old-aluminum-windows-look-new&quot;&gt;How to Make Old Aluminum Windows Look New?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old aluminum windows shouldn’t be put a damper on your house as they are quite easy to renovate. By following the same painting instructions mentioned above, you can turn the entire look of your old windows around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-date-old-windows--how-old-are-my-windows&quot;&gt;How to Date Old Windows? / How old are my windows?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The material of the window can reveal a lot about its approximate age. Wood is the popular choice and has been throughout the ages. So, to date wooden windows you will have to take a careful look at its make and designs. Solid vinyl windows can mean that they are relatively recent. Aluminum and fiberglass windows are quite popular nowadays. These materials are pretty sturdy in make and don’t require replacement as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take an estimated guess of the age of your windows by observing its hardware too. By noticing its latches and pins and its support method such as pegs, latches or springs, you can date it to the decades they became popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;takeaway&quot;&gt;Takeaway&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who doesn’t want their house to look warm and inviting? Your windows play a key role in giving off that impression. Your aluminum window frames, just like every other element of your house, require care and maintenance. Keeping your frames clean and giving them a paint job from time to time will keep them looking brand new.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="SEO" /><category term="B2C" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html">Can I Paint My Aluminum Window Frames?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Press Release Sample</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/press-release/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Press Release Sample" /><published>2021-05-05T20:20:32+02:00</published><updated>2021-05-05T20:20:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/press-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/press-release/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ifeel-madrid-based-health-tech-startup-with-an-aim-to-democratize-access-to-therapy-raises-55m&quot;&gt;ifeel, Madrid based health-tech startup with an aim to democratize access to therapy, raises €5.5M&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ifeels-mission-is-to-facilitate-personalized-online-therapy-with-the-help-of-licensed-health-professionals-based-on-a-subscription-model&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ifeel’s mission is to facilitate personalized online therapy with the help of licensed health professionals, based on a subscription model.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Madrid, Spain., May. 5, 2021&lt;/strong&gt; – ifeel, the disruptive mental health-focused startup, has scored €5.5M in Series A funding led by pan-European Venture Capital firm, Nauta Capital.&lt;br /&gt;
Ifeel is reimagining people’s approach towards caring for their mental health, both on personal and professional fronts. Founded in 2017 as a customer-centric platform, it transitioned to a hybrid model in 2020, answering to a rise in demand from companies looking to invest in the mental well-being of their employees. So, the service is available starting with weekly subscriptions for individuals or under employer’s or insurance provider’s cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ifeel stands out from mindfulness apps and other therapy platforms with the help of its AI-powered platform and range of services that focus on providing personalized support. It facilitates one-on-one video therapy sessions with licensed psychologists along with delivering self-care tools like daily mood trackers, guided chats and recommended activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The health crisis and new blended employment models create a high need for managers to support remote employees and distant customers”, says Amir Kaplan, CEO, and co-founder of ifeel. “We believe smart emotional support services will be a must-have benefit in the near future as the impact is so high. The safe and anonymous access to ifeel allows employees to improve their life with no need of manager referral,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comment from Jordi Vinas, General Partner at Nauta Capital aligns with the company’s mission. “We believe iFeel’s approach has an edge over competitors, thanks to having a holistic platform that covers both prevention and intervention and that includes multiple user touchpoints (self-care tools and guided chat and 1-on-1 video therapies), combined with its full integration to business and distribution partners and its global coverage in several languages. We’re excited to join the team in their journey to truly transform the emotional well-being space.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following a monumental shift in how we define ‘working’ nowadays, it makes complete sense to acknowledge the mental toll it has and will require going forward. ifeel aims to be the bold new solution that equips you with its unique set of self-care tools and therapy services to care for your mental health and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About ifeel&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ifeel aims to democratize therapy and remove the luxurious aspect attached to it. It’s an AI-powered, emotional well-being platform that offers one-on-one therapy sessions with licensed psychologists and various other self-care tools to empower you to take better care of your mental health. Learn more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifeel.com/en/&quot;&gt;ifeelonline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ankita Parida</name></author><category term="Press Release" /><category term="Marketing" /><category term="B2B" /><category term="Sample" /><summary type="html">ifeel, Madrid based health-tech startup with an aim to democratize access to therapy, raises €5.5M ifeel’s mission is to facilitate personalized online therapy with the help of licensed health professionals, based on a subscription model.</summary></entry></feed>